## PHILIPP BLUME

**510.499.6466** 

pgbluster@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/pgblu

github.com/pgblu

www.pgblu.com

### **SUMMARY**

A former Professor of Music, I became a Developer because I recognize that coding, like music, is a powerful way to communicate with people when language alone is inadequate.

Currently, I'm most interested in getting a language-agnostic understanding of web frameworks and HTTP, as well as integration testing of web services. I also harbor a passion for data visualization, database schema design, and algorithm optimization. My long-term interests lie in the ways that music is delivered over the web.

#### **SKILLS**

Software & Web Development LANGUAGES: Ruby, SQL, Javascript (incl. jQuery/AJAX), bash scripting, Java, C++

FRAMEWORKS: Rails 4, Sinatra

TECHNIQUES AND TOOLS: Test-Driven Development, Git, Agile, Continuous Integration

Languages native speaker of German, native speaker of American English, rudimentary Russian

Outreach & Event Organizing conference hosting, public speaking, music production, artistic direction, grant writing

**Communication** German-English translation, English-German translation

writing, editing, proofreading

Music composition, contemporary music, music theory pedagogy, harmony & voice leading,

counterpoint, orchestration, music analysis, 20<sup>TH</sup>-century music history, intonation theory,

electronic music, ensemble conducting, choir directing

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2013-present GERMAN-ENGLISH TRANSLATOR

Wolfram Research, Champaign, IL

2012-present FOUNDER AND ARTISTIC DIRECTOR

SUONO MOBILE USA

2005–2013 VISITING ASST. PROFESSOR OF COMPOSITION & THEORY

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign

2001–2005 GRADUATE STUDENT INSTRUCTOR

University of California, Berkeley

2000-present FREELANCETRANSLATOR

the International Music Institute Darmstadt and the Ernst von Siemens Music Foundation

# PHILIPP BLUME

**510.499.6466** 

pgbluster@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/pgblu

github.com/pgblu

www.pgblu.com

### **EDUCATION**

2015 DEV BOOTCAMP

(Cohort: Bison 2014)

2006 PH.D., WITH DISTINCTION, IN MUSIC

University of California, Berkeley

1999 ARTIST DIPLOMA IN MUSIC COMPOSITION

Staatl. Hochschule für Musik Freiburg, Germany

1995 **BA, MUSIC WITH HONORS** 

University of California, Berkeley

## **SOFTWARE PROJECTS**

**Patroll** 

URL: <a href="https://github.com/pgblu/to-catch-a-troll">https://github.com/pgblu/to-catch-a-troll</a>

8-day group final project at Dev Bootcamp

**DESCRIPTION**: Online harassment, especially the public display of users' private information known as doxxing—is a growing problem on the 21st-century internet. Patroll is a small but effective step toward counteracting this menace. The app, which is built in Rails, enables users to activate web scrapers, tailored to specific sites, then receive alerts via email and reports in their browsers whenever and wherever their personal data appears.

**RESPONSIBILITIES**: initial setup of the app, integration & deployment, setup of background jobs, building a custom web scraper (built on the Cobweb gem) for the different target websites and exposing the results to our search engine (built on the Sunspot gem/Apache Solr).

**Dryphtwords** 

URL: https://github.com/pgblu/dryphtwords\_public

solo work-in-progress

**DESCRIPTION**: Dryphtwords is a word game of my own invention, and this website, built in Sinatra, serves puzzles to the user, validates their answers, and keeps track of their score. Also, the site provides hints [not yet implemented], and even helps players identify and create new puzzles through a WordExplorer model.

**Bison Overflow** 

URL: https://github.com/pgblu/bison-overflow

3-day group project at Dev Bootcamp

**DESCRIPTION**: A clone of stackoverflow.com, built in Rails.

## COMPOSITION

Composition Work Please visit <u>www.pgblu.com/compositions.html</u> for a complete worklist.

Writings & Lectures

**Teaching** Please visit <u>www.pgblu.com/teaching.html</u> for a list of university-level courses taught. **Honors & Awards** Please visit <u>www.pgblu.com/awards.html</u> for a list of music-related honors and awards. Please visit <u>www.pgblu.com/research.html</u> for a list of music-related publications

and lecture appearances.